Kalaipriya Kannan

Business Analyst | SME L&D Data and Reporting

Professional Summary

Certified Scrum Master having and Seasoned Business Analyst offering 9 years of industry success. Expert on business and systems requirements, user acceptance testing and end-user training. Diligent professional with strong communication and task prioritization skills. Worked on diversified portfolio such as Life Sciences, Healthcare, Blockchain Frameworks and L&D Data Reporting. Strong experience in Business Analysis and Data Analysis, proficient in SQL, Tableau.

Work History

Carelon Global Solutions

04/2021 - Current

- Acting as lead point of contact for L&D Data and Reporting
- Working in parallel projects (L&D active and Blockchain frameworks - shadowing) assisting the leadership in decision making for application deployments
- Created dashboards to monitor and track key performance indicators. Generated business intelligence reports to inform strategic decision-making.
- Working with the development team to understand the technical needs and managing the sprint cycle
- Developed business solutions leveraging existing technology to meet the requirements of key stakeholders, product leadership teams, and steering committees
- Improved business direction by prioritizing customers and implementing changes based on collected feedback.
- Conducted interviews with key business users to collect information on business processes and user requirements.
- Generated ad-hoc reports and metrics to evaluate specific business requirements.
- Supported leadership team with reporting, analysis, and business presentations to inform divisional strategies.
- Lead end-to-end release and implementation life cycles of product enhancements by ensuring project requirements are met with optimal business results

Deloitte USI

05/2017 - 03/2021

 With strong experience in the areas of change and release management, defect analysis, system configuration, stakeholder communication and providing training related to new learning solutions

★ kalaipriya.kannan@gmail.com



+91-9840511730

Skills

- Business needs analysis
- Project & Team Management
- Requirement Analysis
- Agile Methodologies
- Data Analysis & Reporting
- Business Consulting & Advisory
- Strategic Planning

Education

05/2014

B.Tech: Information Technology Vel Tech Institutions, Chennai

Certifications

- Certified Scrum Master (PSM1)
- Certified Blockchain Expert (CBE)
- IBM Certified Big Data and Data Science foundations & essentials
- Project Management Fundamentals by Industry expert Chris Croft
- Agile Scrum Master by Agile Project Management Academy

Technical Skills

- SQL
- Tableau
- Python
- Advanced Excel
- HTML
- Postman

- Acted as the escalation point of contact for various learning leads across EMEA and APAC region, directly interact with the vendor for any change requests or enhancement requests basis the need
- Collaborated with a team of Project Owners, Project Managers to provide functional release per sprint cycle
- Assisted the management with backlog refinement sessions
- Identified and implemented operational improvements, enhancements, customizations and rolling out learning solutions that arise from the need analysis, communications & project management
- Facilitated various user groups meeting with learning leaders across the member firms in the different geographical regions for the best practices and gaining consensus visioning to business growth
- Evaluated team's performance and provided coaching to address inefficiencies. Evaluated customer needs and feedback to drive product and service improvements.
- Created and managed project plans, timelines and budgets.

Cognizant Technology Solutions

07/2014 - 04/2017

- Worked on L&D requirements and delivered to meet client needs for functionality and organization development.
- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality prior to release.
- Developed need based training modules for developing multi skilled work force and mentored the new team members to come up the learning curve
- Managed the team of 12 for a large pharmaceutical client in the UK with focus on excelling business targets & service delivery metrics
- Monitored and evaluated metrics, prepared reports on standards & performance target
- Ensured quality services are provided and document functionalities are maintained

Tools Worked

- JIRA
- Jupiter Notebook
- ServiceNow
- Salesforce
- Remedy
- MS SQL Server
- Oracle DB

LMS Worked

- SuccessFactors
- Plateau
- Saba Cloud
- Corner Stone on Demand (CSOD)
- Workday
- Oracle LMS

Blockchain Frameworks

- Hyperledger Fabric
- Ethereum (Permissioned & Private networks)